異常だ 何もかも
This isn’t normal…
None of this is.
痛む？
Does it hurt?
Something is really wrong here.
おかしいよ どうかしてる
ナメクジが あんなふうに
進化するなんて
Why would slugs evolve like that?
だけど… 八丁標でも
近いことが起きてる
It’s sort of similar to what happens at the Holy Barrier.
意識のフィルターから
こぼれ落ちた呪力は
Cantus constantly leaks through our consciousness.
絶えず漏出している
それが八丁標の
外へ向かうことで…
It’s directed outside the Holy Barrier, so—
何？
What?
Huh? What was I saying?
うう… 私 今 何て言った？
大丈夫？ 少し休もうか
Are you okay? Should we rest for a bit?
Let’s take a break.
少し休みましょう
呪力の漏出… 違う 私じゃない
Cantus leakage…
No, it wasn’t me.
誰？
Then who was it?
Episode 23
The Face
of the Boy
The people living in Japan imagine Tokyo as Hell on Earth.
日本中に住む多くの人々は
東京が地獄そのものだという
イメージを持っている
誰かが東京のことを考えるたびに
Whenever someone thinks of Tokyo, their
Cantus leakage produces the hell they expect.
漏出した呪力は
ここを ますます
本物の地獄に変えていく
あっ 何？ 鈴虫？
Huh? Crickets?
What you hear are cockroaches.
ここで鳴いているのは
全て ゴキブリです
馬追いゴキブリ
鉦叩ゴキブリなどで…
Horsechaser cockroaches, bellringer cockroaches, and…
Okay, stop! Sorry for asking!
もういい ごめん ごめん
早季 電池が切れたら
どうするんだよ
Saki, what if it runs out of power?
ごめん…
Sorry…
あっ…
どうした？
What’s wrong?
何でもない 気のせい…
Nothing. Just my imagination.
影が！
The shadow!
Fire! Scare it away with fire!
火を！ 炎で追い払うんです！
What is this?
何なの これ？
逃げましょう！
We should run.
I think we are far enough now.
かなり引き離したはずです
あれは それほど速く
移動できません
It does not move particularly quickly.
あれは何だ？
What was that?
分かりません
I do not know,
but during my previous expedition here, that shadow claimed the most lives.
しかし 前回の探検で
最も多くの犠牲者を出したのが
あの｢影｣でした
あれに捕まって助かった者は
おりません
None escaped its hold.
あの｢影｣の正体を教えてくれ！
Tell us what that shadow was.
クロゴケダニです
Black widow mites.
A carnivorous species of mites. They hunt in swarms.
肉食性のダニで
集団で狩りを行います
致死的な神経毒を持っており
They possess a lethal neurotoxin and
prey upon most lifeforms in the caves,
洞窟内の ほとんどの生物を補殺し
柔らかい体組織を食い尽くします
devouring the soft tissue of their victims.
とにかく 前進し続けないと！
Anyway, we must move on.
It must have been eaten by the shadow.
｢影｣に食われたようですな
私の部下も
骨と皮だけになっていました
Nothing but skin and bones
remained of my soldiers as well.
The enemy appears to have split into two parties underground.
敵は地下で
二手に分かれたようですな
互いに あの音で連絡を取りながら
They communicate using those sounds while searching for us.
我々を捜索しています…
それとは別に 地上を進んでいる
部隊も存在するようです
There are also troops on the surface.
何て言ってるか分かるの？
Do you understand their signals?
いや 正確には分かりません
Not entirely.
しかし 今のところ
But it seems they do not know our position yet.
我々の位置は
つかんでいないようです
ちょっと見てください！
あっ…
Look at this!
先へ進むには
この川を遡る必要があります
We need to travel upstream to reach our goal.
無理だろう
ここじゃ イカダも作れない
Impossible.
We can’t build a raft here either.
泳ぐのは いくらなんでも
危険すぎる
Swimming would be far too risky.
思い切って 地上に出ようか？
Why don’t we cut our losses and return to the surface?
賛成できませんな
ヤツらは鳥を使っています
I find that unwise.
They are using birds.
発見は あっという間でしょう
They would discover us immediately.
We might also run into the fiend or get ambushed.
後は いきなり狙撃か
悪鬼が現れて…
どうしたらいいの？
What should we do, then?
こちらも 二手に分かれましょう
Let us split into two groups as well.
一隊は 今来た洞窟を戻って
追手を違う方向へ誘導するように
Two of us will return to the caves and lead our
pursuers away with our scent, then return here.
臭いをつけてから
ここに戻ってきます
In the meantime, the other two will descend
to a lower level and go back the way we came.
その間に
もう 一隊は下の階層に移り
元 来た方角へと引き返すのです
引き返す？
Go back?
What do you mean?
どういうことだ？
We are bringing the submarine here.
あの潜水艇を取ってくるのです
この川を遡るために
We need it to travel up this river.
どうしても必要ですから
ウソでしょ？
No way…
あんなもん どうやって
ここまで持って来るんだよ？
How are we going to get it here?
この地下河川は海に注いでいます
This underground river must flow into the sea.
However, we saw no river mouth.
しかし 岸辺に河口は
ありませんでした
つまり 海中に開口部があるのです
Consequently, it must be underwater.
潜水艇なら比較的安全に
ここまで来られるはずです
Taking the submarine here would be relatively safe.
ああっ！…
大丈夫ですか？
Are you all right?
水がなければ楽なんですけど…
I could do without the water…
At least the mites are gone, thanks to it.
しかし 水のおかげで
あのダニは いないようですね
きっと うまくいきますよね？
We’ll be fine, right?
正直に言いますが
私には何とも言えません
To be honest, I don’t know.
Everything here was beyond my imagination.
何もかもが
私の予想を超えているので
そうですか…
I see…
But I’ll make sure you survive no
matter what happens, Watanabe-san.
しかし どんなことがあっても
渡辺さんには
生き延びてもらいたいと
思っています
そのためには ベストを尽くします
I will do my utmost to that end.
ありがとう 乾さんに
言ってもらうと心強いです
Thank you.
It’s reassuring to hear that from you, Inui-san.
猛者ぞろいの鳥獣保護官の
You’re the only survivor of our fierce
Wildlife Protection officers, after all.
唯一の生き残りですもんね
Survivor?
生き残りですか
I’m sorry!
あっ… ごめんなさい 私… つい
I didn’t mean to…
いや 違うんです 私には どうも
That’s not what I meant.
I just never considered myself a survivor.
生き残りというのが
ピンと来ないんです
To me it seems more like I escaped death.
死に損ないと言った方が
正しいのかもしれません
そんな…
そうなんですよ
But…
That’s how it is.
私は 家族より深い紐帯で
結ばれていた仲間を失いました
The comrades I lost were closer to me than my family.
私が死ななかったのは
ただの偶然にすぎなかった
Surviving them was mere chance.
亡霊みたいなものです
I’m like a ghost.
仲間の無念を晴らしてやりたい
I want to avenge my comrades.
That’s all that keeps me bound to this life.
そのためだけに命を長らえている
だから あの悪鬼だけは
どうしても許すことができない
The fiend will pay for this.
はい
Yes…
約束してください 私が志半ばで
倒れることになっても
Please promise me.
Promise me you will stop the fiend even if I fall before completing our mission.
あなたが 必ず悪鬼を
止めるということを
約束します
I promise.
奇狼丸？
Kiroumaru?
どこまで信用できるのか
疑問があります
I’m not sure how much we can trust him.
ヤツが かつて
ここを訪れたということ自体
It’s already suspicious how he’s been here before.
おかしな話です 何をしに来たのか
What did he come here for?
私の知っている奇狼丸は
A single loss of life would normally
prompt Kiroumaru to retreat immediately.
最初の犠牲者が出た時点で
引き上げると思います
兵の３分の１を失うほどの
痛手を負うまで探索を続けるのは
Something very important must have motivated him to keep exploring at the cost of a third of his force.
かなりの理由を感じます
何も 後ろ暗いところがなかったら
きちんと説明するはずです
He would’ve explained his reasons if he had nothing to hide.
There’s something else, too.
もう１つ あるんです
どんな？
What is it?
もうすぐ分かると思います
We will soon know.
もうすぐ？
Soon?
海岸に着いたら
きっと 分かるんだと思います
We will know once we arrive on the shore.
あっ…
コウモリですよ
Bats.
これはいい！
えっ？
Excellent!
ヤツらの鳥をごまかせる！
Their birds can’t see us now!
Please wait.
待ってください
えっ？
But they’ll find us if we don’t hurry!
早く行かないと見つかっちゃう
Don’t you remember he said the shore is dangerous at night?
夜間に海岸に近づくのは
危険だと言われたのを
覚えていますか？
That’s right. Kiroumaru said that.
そうだ… 奇狼丸が…
What’s the most dangerous creature around here?
この付近で
最も危険な生き物は何？
…あれ 何か変
Huh? It’s acting strange.
—ous creature is considered to be the giant Bobbit worm.
…生き物が 大鬼磯女と考えら…
…に住むゴカイの 一種で…
夜行性…
They are a species of ragworms that live on—
nocturnal—
雌雄がペアとなる… 特に危険と…
During the mating season, they—
particularly dangerous—
ああ 壊れちゃった！
Oh no, it’s broken!
It must be out of power.
電池が切れたんでしょう
Let’s recharge it later.
また充電すれば動きますよ
でも これが動かないと
水路が どこか…
But how will we find the river without it?
後で考えましょう
Let’s think about that later.
今は そのゴカイに注意して
潜水艇に乗り込むのが先です
We should board the submarine now and look out for the ragworm.
ゴカイって？
Ragworm?
大きなムカデを想像しておけば
いいんだと思います
It will probably look like a giant centipede.
何で奇狼丸は そのことを… あっ
Why didn’t Kiroumaru—
Hence my suspicion.
疑問の理由です
He knew we’d arrive on the beach
after sundown, yet he didn’t warn us.
日没を過ぎて海岸に着くことを
分かっていて
なぜ 警告を発さなかったのか
覚 大丈夫でしょうか？
Will Satoru be all right?
Perhaps Kiroumaru simply had
more pressing matters on his mind.
急な事態で それどころじゃ
なかったのかもしれません
行きましょう
Let’s go.
この時間は まだ怪物は…
It seems like the monster is still—
乾さん！
Inui-san!
キャ～！
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
There might be more of them!
まだ いるかもしれません
We need to get away from here.
早く ここを離れましょう
うう… はい
Okay…
早季…
Saki…
早季
Saki.
Who are you?
誰なの？
It’s me, Saki.
早季 僕だよ
Who?
あなたは…
僕の名前は
まだ思い出せないんだね
I see you still can’t remember my name.
But don’t worry. I’m always with you.
でも いいんだよ
ずっと 一緒だから
僕は 君の心の中に住んでいるんだ
I live in your heart.
心の中に？
In my heart?
That’s right.
そうだよ 呪力とは
Cantus is the power that etches our thoughts into the outside world.
思いを外の世界に
刻み込む能力のことだ
Our souls are, in the end, our thoughts.
そして 人の魂とは
煎じ詰めれば 思いに他ならない
僕の魂の 一部は
A part of my soul is etched deep within your heart.
君の心の奥底に
刻み込まれているんだよ
What happened to you?
あなたは
一体 どうなってしまったの？
忘れてしまったの？
Did you forget?
That’s fine.
でも かまわない
いつか思い出すから
You’ll remember eventually.
せめて名前を教えて
At least tell me your name!
You know my name.
君は僕の名前を知ってるよ
でも 心の中に
障害物が置かれているせいで
Somebody’s left a barrier in your mind that prevents you from remembering.
思い出すことが
できないだけなんだ
Watanabe-san, are you okay?
渡辺さん 大丈夫ですか？
あっ… ええ 大丈夫です
Yes, I’m fine.
早季
Saki…
Saki.
早季 何も心配はいらない
You don’t have to worry.
そのことだけを言いたかったんだ
That’s all I wanted to tell you.
でも 私は本当に悪鬼を倒せるの？
But can I really defeat that fiend?
Fiend? You misunderstand.
悪鬼？ 君が誤解しているんだよ
That’s no fiend.
あれは悪鬼なんかじゃ…
Watanabe-san! Come on!
渡辺さん！
あっ…
しっかりしてください！
大丈夫ですか？
Are you all right?
Y-Yes, sorry about that.
ああ… ええ ごめんなさい
I was just nodding off.
ちょっと ウトウトしてたみたい
浮上します
浮上？
Let’s surface.
Now?
Yes.
はい 流れが緩やかになりました
The flow has slowed and I can see what I believe to be the surface.
水面らしきものも見える
I think we are in a rather spacious tunnel.
かなり広いトンネルに
出たようです
ずいぶん広いですね
What a vast cavern.
人工的に造られた空間みたいだ
It almost seems man-made.
星？
Stars?
Glowworms.
ツチボタルだわ
A perfect moment in a perfect world.
完璧な瞬間 完璧な世界
あの光景を見せてくれたのは…
The one who showed it to me was…
What’s wrong?
どうしました？
Nothing… Never mind.
ええ… いいえ 何でもないんです
I remembered.
思い出した
あの光景を見せてくれたのは
I was certain it was the faceless boy who showed it to me.
間違いなく 顔のない少年だった
もうすぐ充電が完了します
It will be fully charged soon.
ありがとう
Thank you.
You can do some amazing things.
こんなことができるなんて
すごいと思います
I’d be helpless by myself.
私１人だったら
どうしようもなかった
It’s nothing special from a technical perspective.
いや 技術的には それほど
難しいことでもないんです
I just feed it electricity with my Cantus directly.
呪力で 直接
電力を送り込むだけです
Let’s go.
行きましょう これ以上
時間を空費するわけにはいかない
We have no more time to waste.
でも 覚たちを見捨てるのは…
We can’t just leave the others behind!
無事でいると信じましょう
We’ll have to trust that they’re safe.
They might be hiding somewhere, unable to move about.
どこかに隠れて 身動きが
取れなくなってるのかもしれない
我々には大切な使命があります
We have an important mission.
There isn’t enough room to enter with the submarine.
こいつが入れる隙間はないですね
呪力で穴を開けたら？
Can we use Cantus to open a hole?
洞窟全体が崩落したら 終わりです
We’re done for if the cave collapses.
The target is close by, right?
目的地は もうすぐなんでしょう？
Less than a hundred meters in linear distance.
直線距離では100ｍほどです
The stairs of exit A19 in front of us lead directly to the building.
前方にあるＡ19の出口から
階段を上がれば 直接ビルの…
お前は水につかっても
大丈夫なのか？
Are you waterproof?
完全防水仕様で
13気圧 水深120ｍまで…
I am completely waterproof
and operational until 13 bar pressure or 120 meters depth.
私が先に行きます
I’ll go first.
何かあったとき １人では
どうしようもないでしょう？
Let’s not split up. Otherwise we’re helpless.
ゲホッ ゲホッ…！
Shun!
瞬！
待って！
Wait!
Wait, Shun!
待って 瞬！
どうして？
Why?
Shun…
瞬…
Nani mo iranai
何もいらない
I need nothing else
Anata ga ireba ii
あなたがいればいい
When you are by my side
Sotto yokogao iki wo korosu
そっと横顔 息を殺す
I look at you in profile and hold my breath
Mabataki sureba kieteshimaisou de
まばたきすれば消えてしまいそうで
I'm afraid it might vanish like an illusion if I blink now
Mitsumesasete suki da yo
凝視めさせて好きだよ
Let me look at you, I love you
Ah kigi ga furue furidashita yuki
ああ 木々が震え 降り出した雪
The trees shake in the wind and snow gathers on the ground
Ashiato futatsu shiroku
足跡 ふたつ 白く
Two lines of white footprints show
Toki yo tsumore
時よ 積もれ
Snowflakes of time, gather
Kami ni mune ni futari dake no yume ni
髪に 胸に ふたりだけの夢に
In our hair, our hearts, our dream
Sakenai hana no
咲けない花の
This flower cannot bloom
Tane wa yuki ni dakare
種は雪に抱かれ
And the snow embraces its seeds
Yorisou no
寄り添うの
As they huddle together
Shizuka ni wasureraretai
静かに忘れられたい
Quietly they wish to be able to forget
FROM
THE
NEW
WORLD
おかしいぞ 変だと思わないか？
Something is wrong.
Don’t you think so?
早季 逃げろ！
Run, Saki!
聞こえるだろう？
You can hear it, right?
We’ve been played!
最初から だまされていたんだ！
危ない…
Watch out!
I’ll put an end to it with this!
これで終わりにする！
だめ… やめて！
No! Stop!